Thomas Milton Maestas

Albuguergue, NM www.thomasmaestas.net thomas.maestas@hotmail.com 505.508.7707

Web-App Developer

I specialize in latest technologies, with a Masters- level understanding of data analytics. My experience includes both qualitative and methods, quantitative research from interviewing in Spanish to predictive modeling using R. With six years' front-end website contracting experience, I focus on app using data visualization with development JavaScript data driven documents (D3js), R, and Python programming language.

Data Analysis/Visualization Skills

- > OLS Linear & Hierarchical Regression
- R 3.4, Python 2.7-3.6, SPSS 22, Stata 14, SQL
- Interviewing, Survey, Mixed Methods Research Experience. Fluent French & written Spanish

Development Skills

- > Dev tools: D3js, NPM, Node.js, Gulp, AdobeCC, Webpack, Babel, MongoDB, React, SASS-CSS3, Python Django, Plot.ly
- > BASH: iOS, Win & UNIX cli, Git, IS unit testing
- ➤ Blockchain tools : Solidity, Metamask, GETH

Education

M.A. (Dec. 2015) Sociology. University of New Mexico, Albuquerque NM.

History (Cum laude). University of New Mexico, Albuquerque NM, Minor: French. B.A. (Dec. 2001)

Employment

July 2017 - Jan. 2018, Xpansiv Data Systems, Albuquerque, NM (San Francisco, CA). App Developer

Fall 2016, Département de Sociologie, l'Université de Montréal, Québec. Teaching Assistant

Program Evaluator Jan. 2016-May 2016, Pivot Evaluation, Albuquerque, NM

Project Assistant Sept. 2015-Dec. 2015, TRIO Student Support Services, UNM, Albuquerque, NM.

Fall 2013-Spr. 2014, Statistical Analysis Center at Institute for Social Research, UNM, Research Assistant

Albuquerque, NM.

Achievements

Conference Presenter 2016 American Sociological Association (ASA) Annual Conference in Seattle, WA, August 21, 2016; 2015 ASA Annual Conference in Chicago, IL, August, 2015.

Principle Investigator 2013-2014 Ethnographic Mixed-Method Research Project, IRB #13-223 (with Faculty

Sponsor, Dr. Rich Wood). Year-long study completed and included in thesis.

Certification Collaborative Institutional Training Initiative (CITI) Certification Renewal, 2015;

Certificate of Responsible Conduct of Research, 2015; Test Français International, 2016

Service Volunteering Speech & Debate Tournament Judge, 2017-18. Secretary, GPSA Rep. for UNM Dept.

of Sociology Graduate Student Assoc. 2013-15. Pro Bono Webmaster Giftgivers

Anonymous, 2013-16